<root source="https://tradingeconomics.com/china/services-pmi/news">
    <news>
        <title>China Services Growth at 9-Month Low</title>
        <preview>The Caixin China General Services PMI declined to 50.6 in June 2025, down from May’s 51.1 and below market expectations of 51.0. The reading marked the weakest expansion in the services sector since September 2024, as growth in new orders slowed and foreign sales saw their sharpest decline since December 2022, amid subdued global conditions. In response, employment declined marginally. On the price front, input costs rose slightly due to higher raw material and fuel prices, although overall input inflation eased to a three-month low. Meanwhile, selling prices fell for a fifth consecutive month, marking the steepest drop since April 2022, driven by intense market competition. Finally, business sentiment improved for the second straight month on hopes of better economic conditions and stronger sales, though it remained well below the long-run average.</preview>
        <date>2025-07-03</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Services Sector Growth Accelerates in May</title>
        <preview>The Caixin China General Services PMI rose to 51.1 in May 2025, up from April’s seven-month low of 50.7 and in line with market forecasts. The latest reading signaled a stronger expansion in the services sector, supported by faster growth in new business and activity, despite a renewed decline in new export orders due to uncertainty over US tariffs. New export orders fell for the first time in 2025, though only marginally, as Trump's tariffs dampened demand. Employment increased for the first time in three months, with the rate of growth being the fastest since last November. Meanwhile, backlogs of work rose at a softer pace. Regarding prices, input cost inflation accelerated to a seven-month high, driven by higher staff expenses and purchasing costs. Output prices declined for the fourth consecutive month amid efforts to support sales in a highly competitive market. Finally, business sentiment strengthened amid hopes of improvements in global economic conditions.</preview>
        <date>2025-06-05</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Services Growth Slows to 7-Month Low</title>
        <preview>The Caixin China General Services PMI declined to 50.7 in April 2025, down from March’s three-month high of 51.9 and below market forecasts of 51.7. It marked the softest expansion in the services sector since last September, as new orders grew at the slowest pace in 28 months, impacted by disruptions in goods trade amid new US tariffs. Meanwhile, new export business rose only fractionally, with some firms noting improved demand due to rising tourism activity. Employment declined for the second consecutive month amid concerns over rising costs. Regarding prices, input cost inflation accelerated to a three-month high, driven by higher staff expenses and raw material prices. Output prices dropped for the third consecutive month amid efforts to support sales in a highly competitive market. Finally, business sentiment weakened to the second-lowest level since data collection began in November 2005, due to concerns over the negative impact of shifting trade policy.</preview>
        <date>2025-05-06</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Services Growth Hits 3-Month High</title>
        <preview>The Caixin China General Services PMI increased to 51.9 in March 2025, up from 51.4 in the previous month, surpassing market forecasts of 51.6. It marked the strongest growth in the services sector since last December, as new orders rose the most in three months, driven by increases in domestic demand, supported by marketing efforts and a broad improvement in demand conditions. Employment declined modestly, with job shedding being the fastest in nearly a year. Regarding prices, input prices rose after falling fractionally in the previous month, due to higher staff expenses and greater supplier charges. Output prices fell for the second straight month and the steepest drop in six months amid heightened market competition. Lastly, business sentiment moderated amid concerns over the global economic and geopolitical outlooks.</preview>
        <date>2025-04-03</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Services Growth Unexpectedly Strengthens</title>
        <preview>The Caixin China General Services PMI unexpectedly advanced to 51.4 in February 2025, up from January’s four-month low of 51.0, surpassing market forecasts of 50.8. The increase was supported by a modest rise in new business, amid an improvement in market demand. Foreign sales rose for the second consecutive month, growing solidly and reaching its highest level in three months. Employment increased fractionally, after falling for the previous two months, and helped firms largely stay on top of their overall workloads. On prices, input prices fell for the first time since June 2020, due to lower market demand and a reduction in raw material prices. As a result, selling prices dropped marginally as firms sought to pass on reduced input costs and offer promotional discounts in a competitive market environment. Finally, sentiment improved to a three-month high amid hopes of stronger market demand and better economic conditions.</preview>
        <date>2025-03-05</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Services Growth Hits 4-Month Low</title>
        <preview>The Caixin China General Services PMI unexpectedly declined to 51.0 in January 2025, down from December’s seven-month high of 52.2, and below market forecasts of 52.3. The latest reading marked the softest expansion in the services sector since September, as new business growth eased to a four-month low, employment fell the most since April 2024, and selling price inflation slowed. Sales growth was driven by higher domestic demand and new foreign sales after export orders had fallen in December. Meanwhile, employment declined for the second straight month due to resignations and redundancies. On prices, input price inflation accelerated to a three-month high due to higher raw material and labor costs. As a result, selling prices increased for the 2nd consecutive month, though at a slower pace than in December, due to the support for sales. Finally, sentiment improved but remained below average amid concerns over heightened competition and the impact of trade uncertainties on demand.</preview>
        <date>2025-02-05</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Services Growth Hits 7-Month High</title>
        <preview>The Caixin China General Services PMI increased to 52.2 in December 2024 from 51.5 in November, surpassing market forecasts of 51.7. The latest reading marked the fastest expansion in the services sector since May, supported by greater new business inflows. Sales growth was notably driven by higher domestic demand, as new export business fell for the first time since August 2023 amid softening foreign interest. Meanwhile, employment declined for the first time in four months, due to resignations and cost concerns. On the cost side, input price inflation accelerated for the first time in three months, though it remained only marginally, driven by higher material and wage costs. As a result, selling prices increased for the first time since June, as firms sought to pass on rising cost burdens to clients. Finally, sentiment weakened to the second-lowest level since March 2020, amid concerns over rising competition and the negative economic outlook for international trade.</preview>
        <date>2025-01-06</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Caixin Service PMI Unexpectedly Falls</title>
        <preview>The Caixin China General Services PMI declined to 51.5 in November 2024 from October's three-month high of 52.0, missing market forecasts of 52.5. The latest reading indicated a slowdown in the growth of new business and foreign sales. Meanwhile, employment increased for the third consecutive month, though only marginally, with a modest rise in backlogs of work for the fourth month. On the cost side, input price inflation fell to its lowest in 53 months, staying below the series average. Output prices decreased for the third time in four months, due to intensified competition. Lastly, business confidence reached a seven-month high, fueled by optimism about improved economic conditions and supportive government policies potentially boosting sales. " Service providers generally expressed confidence in market improvement amid policy support, although some were concerned about the future trade environment," said Dr. Wang Zhe, senior economist at Caixin Insight Group.</preview>
        <date>2024-12-04</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Services PMI Beats Estimates</title>
        <preview>The Caixin China General Services PMI increased to 52.0 in October 2024, up from September's one-year low of 50.3 and surpassing market forecasts of 50.5, after Beijing launched a series of support measures in late September. This marked the highest reading since July, as new business inflows grew for the first time in four months, with a solid rise in export orders. Meanwhile, employment increased for the second consecutive month, though only marginally, while backlogs of work rose slightly for the third straight month. On the cost side, input prices increased due to higher material and energy costs, although the inflation rate eased to a three-month low and remained below the series average. Output prices, meanwhile, stabilized after two consecutive months of decline. Finally, business confidence improved to a five-month high, rebounding from September's four-and-a-half-year low amid hopes for better economic conditions and increased promotional efforts.</preview>
        <date>2024-11-05</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Caixin Services PMI Lowest in A Year</title>
        <preview>The Caixin China General Services PMI slipped to 50.3 in September 2024 from 51.6 in the previous month, below market forecasts of 51.5. It was the lowest figure since September 2023, as new orders expanded at the softest pace in near a year despite a solid expansion of export business. Meanwhile, employment returned to growth, albeit only marginally. At the same time, backlogs increased for the second month as a result of rising new work inflows. On the cost side, input prices increased, with the rate of inflation above the series average to the highest in almost 2-1/2 years, on higher input material, labor, and energy costs. However, output prices fell for the second month, the fourth time that selling prices have declined in the past three years, due to attempts to support sales. Lastly, confidence weakened to the lowest since March 2020, dragged by headwinds from global economic outlook and rising competition.</preview>
        <date>2024-09-30</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Services Sector Growth Below Forecasts</title>
        <preview>The Caixin China General Services PMI declined to 51.6 in August 2024 from 52.1 in the previous month, below market forecasts of 52.2, amid easing new order growth and a marginal drop in employment. It was the 20th month of growth in services activity, supported by rising new business and new orders amid better demand conditions, with foreign demand growing faster. In the meantime, employment decreased after increasing in July, and the fifth time decline in the past seven months due to resignations and redundancies stemming from the need to lower costs. On prices, input cost inflation accelerated to the highest since June 2023, boosted by higher material, wages, and transportation costs. Meanwhile, output costs fell for the first time in seven months and the steepest drop since April 2022 amid strong competition and offer discounts to support sales. Finally, business sentiment improved to a three-month high, lifted by hopes of better market conditions and business expansion plans. .</preview>
        <date>2024-09-04</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Services Growth Beats Estimates</title>
        <preview>The Caixin China General Services PMI rose to 52.1 in July 2024 from June’s 8-month low of 51.2, above market forecasts of 51.4. It was the 19th month of growth in services activity, helped by a faster rise in new orders, a sustained rise in export sales, and robust employment. Foreign sales continued to rise supported by growth of tourism activity, despite the rate of expansion eased in the current 11-month sequence. Employment climbed to the fastest in nearly a year after falling in June. On prices, input prices rose due to higher material, labor, and transport costs. Meanwhile, average selling prices were unchanged after rising throughout the past five months. Finally, business sentiment was subdued with the level of business confidence being the second-lowest since March 2020, as firms were cautiously optimistic that improvements in market conditions and business development efforts could support services activity growth in the year ahead.</preview>
        <date>2024-08-05</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Services Growth at 8-Month Low</title>
        <preview>The Caixin China General Services PMI declined to 51.2 in June 2024 from May’s 10-month high of 54.0, below forecasts of 53.4. It marked the 18th straight month of growth in services activity but the softest pace since last October, as new orders and export order growth eased. Employment fell marginally amid resignations and redundancies, pushing increased backlogs of work for the first time in five months. On prices, input prices increased due to higher material, labor, and transport costs. As a result, selling prices rose despite the net rise in charges being marginal. Finally, business sentiment weakened to the lowest since March 2020 amid concerns about downward pressure on the economy and rising competition.</preview>
        <date>2024-07-03</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Services Growth at 10-Month High</title>
        <preview>The Caixin China General Services PMI advanced to 54.0 in May 2024 from 52.5 in April, beating forecasts of 52.6. It was the 17th straight month of expansion in services activity, marking the fastest pace since July 2023, as new business and new export orders grew the most in a year due to strengthening domestic and external demand. Employment increased for the first time in four months, with its growth rate the fastest since September 2023 while backlogs of work continued to decline. On prices, input cost inflation accelerated to an 11-month high, driven by higher input material, labor, and transport costs. As a result, output cost inflation rose to the highest since January 2022 as firms shared their increased cost burdens with clients. Finally, business sentiment remained upbeat but its level of optimism weakened to a seven-month low, amid rising concerns over the global economic outlook and inflation.</preview>
        <date>2024-06-05</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Services Growth Remains Solid</title>
        <preview>The Caixin China General Services PMI was down to 52.5 in April 2024 from 52.7 in March, matching forecasts. It was the 16th straight month of growth in services activity, with new business growing the most in nearly a year, boosted by the latest rise in activity and an improvement in confidence. New order growth accelerated to the fastest since May 2023 amid improved demand conditions and a broadening of customer bases, with foreign sales rising the most in 10 months, lifted by increasing tourism activity. Employment fell for the 3rd straight month due to resignations and redundancies, while backlogs of work remained unchanged. On the cost side, input cost inflation accelerated due to higher raw materials, labor, and energy costs despite being below the series average. Meanwhile, output price inflation rose above the series average as firms sought to share rising cost burdens with clients. Finally, sentiment improved to a four-month high amid hopes of improvement in market prospects.</preview>
        <date>2024-05-06</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Services Growth Accelerates in March</title>
        <preview>The Caixin China General Services PMI increased for the first time in three months to 52.7 in March 2024 from February's three-month low of 52.5, matching market forecasts. It was the 15th straight month of growth in services activity, with new business rising at the fastest pace in the year-to-date. New order growth accelerated amid improvements in demand conditions and business development efforts, with export orders rising the most in nine months. Employment fell for the 2nd straight month, though the rate of job shedding eased from February and was only marginal while the backlog of work declined. On the cost side, input prices rose due to higher raw material, labor, and transport costs despite the inflation easing further below the series average. Meanwhile, output price inflation slowed but remained slightly above their long-term trend. Lastly, sentiment improved for the first time in three months amid hopes of launching new products, expansion plans, and rises in client budgets.</preview>
        <date>2024-04-03</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Services Growth at 3-Month Low</title>
        <preview>The Caixin China General Service PMI moderated for the 2nd straight month to 52.5 in February 2024 from 52.7 in January. It was the 14th straight month of expansion in services activity but the softest pace since last November amid a subdued increase in overall new work. New order growth was little changed and remained slower than the average seen in 2023. However, export orders rose the most in eight months amid reports of firmer customer demand across external markets. Employment fell for the 1st time in three months, with the rate of job shedding being the quickest seen in over a year due to subdued demand conditions. Meantime, outstanding business dropped for the 1st time since July 2022. On the cost side, input prices rose due to higher raw material and fuel costs. Meanwhile, output prices climbed to the fastest since May 2023 as firms looked to pass on additional expenses to customers. Lastly, sentiment weakened to a four-month low amid remaining subdued market conditions.</preview>
        <date>2024-03-05</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Services Growth Eases Slightly</title>
        <preview>The Caixin China General Service PMI inched down to 52.7 in January 2024 from December’s five-month high of 52.9 amid softer rises in new orders. It was the 13th straight month of expansion in services activity, signaling a further solid increase in service sector output, supported by firmer underlying demand conditions and new customer wins. However, export order growth eased, despite only fractionally. In response to the expansion in total new orders, employment rose for the second straight month, with backlogs of work expanding at the fastest pace since last October. On the cost side, input prices rose slightly but below the series average due to higher raw material, labor, and transportation costs. Meanwhile, output prices fell for the first time since April 2022, as many businesses resorted to discounts and other promotions to boost sales due to increased competition. Finally, sentiment weakened to a three-month low and below its historical average.</preview>
        <date>2024-02-05</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Services Sector Growth at 5-Month High</title>
        <preview>The Caixin China General Service PMI increased to 52.9 in December 2023 from 51.5 in November, beating market expectations of 51.6. It was the 12th straight month of growth in services activity and the fastest expansion since July, mainly boosted by a solid rise in new business. New orders grew the most in seven months, with export orders rising for the fourth consecutive month and hitting the highest levels since June. Meanwhile, employment increased for the first time in three months, while backlogs of work were unchanged after rising in each of the prior 16 months. On the cost side, input price inflation hit its highest since July due to higher raw material prices and labor costs. Meantime, output cost inflation eased to a four-month low amid efforts to attract demand and secure new business. Lastly, sentiment strengthened to a three-month high amid hopes of stronger economic conditions and a rise in customer spending. However, it was still below the series average.</preview>
        <date>2024-01-04</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Services Growth at 3-Month High</title>
        <preview>The Caixin China General Service PMI increased to 51.5 in November 2023 from 50.4 in the prior month. It was the 11th straight month of growth in services activity and the fastest expansion since August, amid reports of firmer market conditions. New orders grew the most in three months, indicating that domestic and overseas demand improved, with new export orders rising modestly for the third straight month. Meanwhile, employment fell slightly amid relatively subdued demand conditions, while the rate of backlog accumulation slowed and was only marginal. On the cost side, input price inflation hit its lowest since June 2022 as rises in costs of labor and raw materials were limited. As a result, prices charged rose the least in three months and were broadly in line with the series average. Lastly, sentiment improved for the 1st time in five months amid hopes of rising demand at home and abroad. However, sentiment remained softer than seen on average since the survey began in late 2005.</preview>
        <date>2023-12-05</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Services PMI Edges Higher</title>
        <preview>The Caixin China General Service PMI rose slightly to 50.4 in October 2023 from September's 9-month low of 50.2. It was the 10th straight month of growth in services activity as Beijing continued its efforts to stabilize the economy. Foreign sales grew for the second consecutive month due to an easing of travel curbs that attracted more tourists from abroad while employment stabilized after growing in the prior 8 months. Outstanding business grew further, with the rate of accumulation being the most since January. Meantime, new orders rose the least so far this year due to persistently weak demand. On the cost side, input price inflation hit its lowest since June 2022 as rises in costs of labor, raw materials, and transport were limited. Meantime, prices charged increased the most since May, as firms sought to pass on higher input costs to clients. Finally, sentiment was less upbeat, weakening for the fourth straight month to a 3-1/2 year low, on concerns about the economic outlook.</preview>
        <date>2023-11-03</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Services Sector Growth at 9-Month Low</title>
        <preview>The Caixin China General Service PMI dropped to 50.2 in September 2023 from 51.8 in the previous month, pointing to the softest increase in services activity since the start of the year, as both business activity and new orders grew the least in 2023 to date, as demand remained weak despite a string of support measures. Meanwhile, employment increased for the eighth consecutive month. Notably, the rate of growth was the slowest seen over the current eight-month period of job creation, with backlogs of work rising at the softest pace since February and only slightly overall. On the price front, input cost inflation slowed to a nine-month low while cost inflation accelerated to a three-month high, as firms partly passed on higher cost burdens to clients. Lastly, business sentiment weakened to a ten-month low amid concerns about the market conditions and impact on sales.</preview>
        <date>2023-10-01</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Services Sector Growth at 8-Month Low</title>
        <preview>The Caixin China General Service PMI slipped to 51.8 in August 2023 from 51.9 in July, missing market forecasts of 53.6. It was the softest increase in services activity since the start of the year, amid mounting downward pressure on the economy. New order growth slowed while export sales fell for the first time since last December. Meanwhile, employment increased for the seventh consecutive month. The rate of job creation was little changed from July and modest, amid reports of higher business requirements and plans to expand capacity, with backlogs of work rising due to higher amounts of new orders and subsequent pressure on capacity. On the price front, input cost inflation eased to a six-month low while cost inflation slowed to the lowest level since April, as the market competition was still tight. Finally, business sentiment weakened to a nine-month low.</preview>
        <date>2023-09-05</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Services Growth Unexpectedly Strengthens</title>
        <preview>The Caixin China General Services PMI unexpectedly rose to 54.1 in July 2023 from June’s five-month low of 53.9, exceeding forecasts of 52.5. The reading pointed to the seventh straight month of expansion in services activity amid an accelerated rise in new orders and a further rise in job creation in the summer travel season. New orders growth accelerated, despite foreign demand expanding at a marginal pace that was the slowest for six months amid a sluggish global economic environment. Meanwhile, employment climbed for the sixth consecutive month and the fastest pace in four months, with backlogs of work staying in expansionary territory for the 12th consecutive month. On the price front, input cost inflation eased to a five-month low while cost inflation slowed from the previous month, as the market competition was still tight. Finally, business sentiment weakened to an eight-month low amid concerns about the sustainability of global economic growth.</preview>
        <date>2023-08-03</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Services PMI Drops to 5-Month Low</title>
        <preview>The Caixin China General Services PMI fell to 53.9 in June 2023 from 57.1 in the previous month. The reading pointed to the sixth straight month of expansion in services activity but the softest pace since January amid moderated demand. New orders growth eased to a six-month low and new export business also moderated although it continued to benefit from a revival in tourism and travel since the easing of pandemic restrictions. Meanwhile, employment climbed for the fifth consecutive month, with the speed of job creation being the strongest in three months. On the price front, input prices rose solidly due to elevated staffing costs and higher prices for raw materials while output cost increased only slightly amid strong competition. Finally, business sentiment improved for the first time in five months amid hopes of stronger economic conditions and greater amounts of new work to support growth.</preview>
        <date>2023-07-05</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Service Sector Growth Accelerates</title>
        <preview>The Caixin China General Services PMI increased to 57.1 in May 2023 from 56.4 in the previous month. The reading pointed to the fifth straight month of expansion in services activity and the second-fastest since November 2020 as the post-COVID recovery continued. New orders grew faster with sustained a rise in new export business amid reports of stronger demand while employment climbed for the fourth consecutive month, although the speed of job creation eased. On prices, input cost inflation slowed from April's one-year high but remained solid overall due to elevated staffing costs and higher prices for raw materials. Meanwhile, output cost inflation accelerated to the fastest since February 2022 and above the series average as firms sought to hike their fees again. Lastly, business sentiment remained upbeat, but the level of optimism weakened to a five-month low.</preview>
        <date>2023-06-05</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Service Sector Growth Stays Robust</title>
        <preview>The Caixin China General Services PMI declined to 56.4 in April 2023 from March’s 28-month high of 57.8. Still, it was the fourth straight month of expansion in services activity as the post-COVID recovery continued. Both new orders and foreign sales increased at softer paces while employment grew the least in three months. The rate of accumulation was similar to that seen in the prior period, however, only mild. On the price front, input cost inflation accelerated to a 12-month high due to elevated staffing costs and higher prices for raw materials and office supplies. Meanwhile, output cost inflation rose slightly as firms sought to boost competitiveness and attract sales. Finally, business sentiment deteriorated to a four-month low.</preview>
        <date>2023-05-05</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Services PMI Climbs to 28-Month High</title>
        <preview>The Caixin China General Services PMI increased to 57.8 in March 2023 from 55.0 in February, pointing to the largest expansion in activity since last November 2020, boosted by a sharp rise in new orders and employment after the easing of COVID-19 measures. New orders advanced the most in 28 months, with new export business growing at the quickest rate since the series began in September 2014. Employment rose at the fastest pace since November 2020, while the accumulation rate added on the month but was mild overall. On the price front, input cost inflation accelerated to a seven-month record due to higher wage costs and raw material prices. At the same time, output cost inflation picked up marginally as firms' abilities to pass on higher cost burdens to clients were limited. Finally, business sentiment deteriorated to a three-month low.</preview>
        <date>2023-04-06</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Services Growth Accelerates in February</title>
        <preview>The Caixin China General Services PMI climbed to 55.0 in February 2023, up from 52.9 in the previous month, signaling the fastest pace of expansion in activity since last August. New business rose the most since April 2021, and new export growth hit a nearly four-year high, as the relaxation of COVID-19 restrictions helped lift customer numbers and demand. In addition, employment levels increased for the first time in four months, with job creation accelerating the most since November 2020 and backlogs of work accumulating at the softest rate since last October. On the price front, both input costs and prices charged grew modestly. Finally, business sentiment remained high, despite the degree of optimism slipping from January's near 12-year high.</preview>
        <date>2023-03-03</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Services Activity Returns to Growth</title>
        <preview>The Caixin China General Services PMI increased to 52.9 in January 2023 from 48.0 in December. This was the first growth in the service sector since last August, buoyed by the recent rollback of pandemic curbs and faster-than-expected peaking of infections.. New orders increased for the first time in five months. The modest upturn in new orders was supported by higher customer numbers, with new export business rising the most in 21 months. Meanwhile, employment fell at the softest pace in three months, with backlogs of work increasing at the fastest pace since May 2022. On prices, input cost inflation rose for the first time in five months, due to higher prices of raw material, staff and fuel expenses. Meanwhile, output cost inflation eased amid efforts to attract new business. Finally, sentiment strengthened to the highest for nearly 12 years, buoyed by hopes that the recent loosening of Covid restrictions.</preview>
        <date>2023-02-03</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Services Sector Shrinks at Softer Pace</title>
        <preview>The Caixin China General Services PMI increased to 48.0 in December 2022 from November’s six-month low of 46.7, signaling a softer decline in the sector, and pointing to the 4th straight month of drop, after the country removed its stringent zero-Covid policy. Both activity and new work shrank at softer rates, while outstanding business expanded at the fastest pace since May. Meanwhile, employment continued to fall, due to cost reduction policies and voluntary leavers, with the rate of job shedding was quicker than seen on average in 2022. Meantime, export orders fell for the second time in three months, amid ongoing Covid restrictions in some countries. On prices, input cost inflation eased to a six-month low, with expenses rising marginally overall. Also, firms registered a softer rise in selling prices to a four-month low. Finally, sentiment strengthened to a 17-month high, amid hopes the lifting of Covid restrictions and recovering demand.</preview>
        <date>2023-01-05</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Services Shrinks the Most in 6 Months</title>
        <preview>The Caixin China General Services PMI fell to 46.7 in November 2022 from 48.4 in October, pointing to the 3rd straight month of drop. This was also the steepest contraction in the service sector since May, amid anti-COVID containment measures that weighed on demand and operations. New orders fell the most in six months, employment shrank at the steepest rate since the survey began in November 2005, while backlogs rose at the fastest rate in six months. Meantime, export orders returned to growth as overseas demand picked up following an easing of international travel rules. On prices, input cost inflation eased for the third month in a row, and was among the weakest in over two years. Also, firms registered a slower rise in prices charged, with some of them citing efforts to boost sales. Finally, sentiment hit an eight-month low, significantly below its long-term average, amid concerns over how long it will take to contain the virus and the impact of curbs on their businesses.</preview>
        <date>2022-12-05</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Services Activity Shrinks for 2nd Month</title>
        <preview>The Caixin China General Services PMI deteriorated further to 48.4 in October 2022 from 49.3 in September, contracting for the 2nd straight month and logging the lowest reading since May as China’s services sector sustained a slowdown in activity amid efforts to stop the spread of COVID-19 that disrupted business operations and weighed on demand. Containment measures associated with the latest spate of infections acted to suppress demand, highlighted by a 2nd successive monthly reduction in inflows of new business. Meanwhile, efforts to expand staffing capacity and enhance sales capabilities contributed to a rise in employment. However, businesses reported a 3rd straight monthly rise in backlogs of work at the start of the 4th quarter. Turning to prices, October's survey data pointed to a slightly faster rise in average fees charged by services companies in China. Looking ahead, firms were slightly more optimistic in October though Covid-induced economic concerns persisted.</preview>
        <date>2022-11-03</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Services Sector Shrinks</title>
        <preview>The Caixin China General Services PMI plunged to 49.3 in September 2022 from 55.0 in the prior month. This was the first contraction in services activity since May, amid the severity of the COVID outbreaks in many areas across the mainland. New orders shrank for the first time in four months; while employment dropped for the ninth month running, with the rate of job shedding the steepest pace since May and backlogs grew for the second month in a row. Export orders expanded slightly, however, following an improvement in some foreign markets. On inflation, input cost increased for the 27th consecutive month, due to greater costs for raw materials and labor. That said, the rate of inflation edged down to the lowest since June and was mild. Meantime, fees charged rose at the quickest pace for five months. Looking ahead, sentiment weakened to a six-month low, on concerns over how long the virus and containment measures will impact operations and customer demand.</preview>
        <date>2022-10-08</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Service Sector Growth Stays Robust</title>
        <preview>The Caixin China General Services PMI fell to 55.0 in August from July’s 15-month high of 55.5 amid the recent wave of COVID-19 and the impact of adverse weather. Still, the latest print was the third straight month of growth in services activity, as new orders grew solidly with the rate of increase the second-steepest since October 2021 while broadly in line with the series average. Meantime, new export orders fell for the eighth straight month, down at a steeper rate than that in July; while employment declined for the second month running, with backlogs of work rising after a slight drop in July. On prices, input cost inflation accelerated to a four-month high, as food and marketing costs, labor, and raw materials were higher. Output charged rose fractionally amid efforts to stimulate sales. Finally, confidence strengthened to a nine-month high, attributed to hopes of a recovery in demand and improving the pandemic situation.</preview>
        <date>2022-09-05</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Services Growth at 15-Month High</title>
        <preview>The Caixin China General Services PMI rose to 55.5 in July 2022 from 54.5 in June, pointing to the second straight month of growth. The latest print was also the sharpest pace of expansion in the service sector since April 2021, amid further improvement in the COVID-19 situation after an easing of lockdown measures with new orders rising the most since October 2021. However, new export orders fell for the seventh straight month, and employment fell modestly amid a slight decline in backlogs of work. On prices, input costs were stable, as food prices and wages were higher, but the prices of some bulk commodities fell. Output charged, meanwhile, went up at a marginal rate that was similar to those seen in the prior two months. Finally, confidence was at its strongest since November 2021, lifted by hopes for a recovery in demand. “In general, the eased COVID situation and curbs facilitated a continuous recovery in the economy," said Dr. Wang Zhe, senior economist at Caixin Insight.</preview>
        <date>2022-08-03</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Services Growth at 11-Month High: Caixin</title>
        <preview>The Caixin China General Services PMI surged to 54.5 in June 2022 from 41.4 in May, pointing to the first expansion in the sector in four months, amid improving the domestic COVID-19 situation and loosening lockdown measures. The latest reading also pointed to the sharpest increase in the sector since July 2021, with new orders returning to growth and softer decline in overseas demand. At the same time, employment fell to the softest pace in three months; while the level of outstanding business expanded at only a marginal rate with the rate of backlog accumulation increasing only slightly. On inflation, input cost inflation eased to a 25-month low, while output costs increased at a slower pace, as efforts to boost competitiveness and attract sales restricted overall pricing power. Finally, confidence was little-changed from May and remained below the series average.</preview>
        <date>2022-07-05</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Services Shrink at Softer Pace</title>
        <preview>The Caixin China General Services PMI increased to 41.4 in May 2022 from April's 26-month low of 36.2, while signaling a third successive monthly fall in the sector. The latest reading, however, was the second-sharpest seen since February 2020, during the initial phase of the pandemic. New orders fell for the fourth month in a row, with the rate of drop easing from April's 26-month record but stayed sharp. Meanwhile, foreign orders dropped less, but still marked. At the same time, employment shrank the most in 15 months, with the rate of backlog accumulation being the steepest seen since February 2020. On inflation, input cost inflation slowed to a nine-month low, while output costs climbed after declining in the prior month, reflecting greater prices for labor, raw materials, food, energy and transport. Finally, confidence strengthened to a 3-month high, due to hopes of a strong recovery once the pandemic is brought under control and market conditions normalize.</preview>
        <date>2022-06-06</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Services Shrink the Most in 26 Months</title>
        <preview>The Caixin China General Services PMI sank to 36.3 in April 2022 from 42.0 in March, the second straight month of contraction amid tighter COVID-19 containment measures. The latest print also pointed to the sharpest fall in the sector since the onset of the pandemic in February 2020, with new orders shrinking at the 2nd-sharpest rates since the survey began in November 2005 and export sales fell the most in 2 years. Also, employment shrank for the 4th month running, despite the reading showing only a marginal drop; while the level of outstanding business rose further though the rate of accumulation was slower than that in March. On inflation, input costs rose due to greater costs for raw materials, fuel, and spending on pandemic-protection measures. Meanwhile, output costs fell for the first time in 8 months, amid efforts by some firms to attract new clients by lowering fees. Finally, confidence improved slightly, on optimism that outbreaks would be brought under control.</preview>
        <date>2022-05-05</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Services Shrink the Most in 25 Months: Caixin</title>
        <preview>The Caixin China General Services PMI plunged to 42.0 in March 2022 from 50.2 in February, the first contraction in seven months amid the new wave of COVID-19 outbreaks and mobility restrictions. It was the sharpest fall in the activity of the service since February 2020, as new orders shrank the most in two years and export sales fell at the steepest rate since October 2020. Also, employment dropped for the third month running while outstanding business accelerated the most in three months. On the price side, input cost inflation accelerated with the reading quicker than the series average, due to greater costs for raw materials, energy, food, transport and spending on pandemic-protection measures. Meanwhile, output cost inflation hit a seven-month low, on efforts to attract new business. Finally, confidence was at a 19-month low, on concerns over how long business operations would be impacted by the pandemic and the war in Ukraine.</preview>
        <date>2022-04-06</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Services PMI Drops to 6-Month Low</title>
        <preview>The Caixin China General Services PMI fell to 50.4 in February 2022 from 51.4 in January, marking the lowest reading in the current six-month sequence of growth in services activity. The slowdown reflected recent COVID-19 outbreaks and measures to contain the spread of the virus, with output growing slightly while new orders fell for the first time in six months and both new export business and employment dropped for the second straight month. At the same time, outstanding workloads rose the least in four months, amid signs that capacity pressures moderated. Meanwhile, cost pressures eased, with both input costs and output charges rising at slower rates. Finally, business confidence improved to a three-month high on optimism that the domestic epidemic will be kept under control.</preview>
        <date>2022-03-03</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Services Growth Eases to 5-Month Low</title>
        <preview>The Caixin China General Services PMI fell to 51.4 in January 2022 from 53.1 in December. This was the weakest increase in the current five-month sequence of growth in services activity, reflecting recent COVID-19 outbreaks and measures to stop the spread of the virus. New order growth eased and foreign sales shrank the most in 15 months. Also, employment dropped for first time since last August, amid a marginal rise in outstanding business. Meantime, cost pressures picked up slightly. Neither gauge changed much from December, but the measure for input costs was apparently higher than the one for prices charged. Meanwhile, sentiment was at a 16-month low. “That indicated that service enterprises remained concerned about the ongoing epidemic in China." said Wang Zhe, senior economist at Caixin Insight Group.</preview>
        <date>2022-02-07</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Services Growth Accelerates: Caixin</title>
        <preview>The Caixin China General Services PMI increased to 53.1 in December 2021 from 52.1 in the prior month, marking the fourth straight month of expansion. New orders expanded at a faster pace despite fears over COVID-19 flare-ups, while export orders were stable. At the same time, employment rose for the fourth month in a row and was the fastest increase since May; and backlogs of work expanded for the fifth time in the past six months, accumulating at the steepest pace since February 2020. On the cost front, input prices continued to rise due to labor and raw material costs, but the rate of inflation softened. Meanwhile, output prices inflation slowed to a four-month low. Looking forward, business sentiment weakened to a 15-month low, which was remarkably lower than the long-term average, due to worries uncertainty over the pandemic.</preview>
        <date>2022-01-06</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Services PMI Falls to 3-Month Low</title>
        <preview>The Caixin China General Services PMI declined to 52.1 in November 2021 from 53.8 in the prior month, pointing to the weakest growth in three months, amid a rise in COVID-19 infections. Business activity and new orders expanded at the slowest pace in three months and only marginal overall, and export sales remained mild, while employment rose for the third month in a row and the fastest rate since May. On the cost front, input price inflation accelerated to a six-month high on rising in labour, raw materials, and energy costs. Meanwhile, output prices inflation slowed, due to softer in demand conditions. Looking forward, business sentiment strengthened on expectations that the pandemic will be brought under control globally and demand conditions will improve. “ The resurgence of local Covid-19 outbreaks had a bigger impact on demand than on supply,” Wang Zhe, Senior Economist at Caixin Insight Group said.</preview>
        <date>2021-12-03</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Services PMI Rises to 3-Month High</title>
        <preview>The Caixin China General Services PMI increased to 53.8 in October 2021 from 53.4 in the prior month, pointing to the second straight month of expansion in the service sector and the steepest pace since July as COVID-19 outbreaks eased. New orders expanded the most in three months, export sales returned to growth, and employment rose for the second month in a row. Meantime, backlogs of work were unchanged following a three-month sequence of accumulation. On the cost front, input prices rose for the 16th straight month and increased at the fastest pace in three months on rising labor, and raw material costs; while output cost inflation accelerated to the quickest since July. Looking forward, sentiment weakened to a four-month low, due to concerns over rising costs and supply chain disruption.</preview>
        <date>2021-11-03</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Services Sector Rebounds</title>
        <preview>The Caixin China General Services PMI jumped to 53.4 in September 2021 from 46.7 in the prior month, moving away from the lowest level seen since the height of the pandemic last year. Both new orders and employment bounced back to the expansionary territory, as a major COVID-19 outbreak in the eastern province of Jiangsu eased. At the same time, outstanding business continued to increase, but at a slower pace. Meanwhile, new export sales shrank again, with the sub-index hitting its lowest in seven months due to the surging pandemic overseas. On the cost front, input prices rose for the 15th straight month and increased at a faster pace, on rising labor, freight, and raw material costs. Meantime, prices charged went up after falling in August. Looking forward, sentiment remained optimistic, with the gauge of business expectations rising further into positive territory, though remaining below its long-term average.</preview>
        <date>2021-10-08</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Services PMI Sinks to 20-Month Low: Caixin</title>
        <preview>The Caixin China General Services PMI plunged to 46.7 in August 2021 from 54.9 in the prior month. This was the first contraction in services activity since April 2020, amid a surge in the Delta strain of COVID-19 cases in some parts of the country. New orders shrank for the first time in 16 months, while employment fell for the second time in three months on the back of rising outstanding business. At the same time, new export business was broadly unchanged for the second month running. Prices data showed input prices rising modestly due to higher staffing costs and increased transport fees, while output price fell following a solid increase in July. Looking forward, confidence remained upbeat, though the degree of positive sentiment dipped from July and remained below the series average.</preview>
        <date>2021-09-03</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Services Growth Accelerates Sharply: Caixin</title>
        <preview>The Caixin China General Services PMI climbed to 54.9 in July 2021 from a 14-month low of 50.3 in June, signaling a sharp and accelerated expansion of services activity amid the successful containment of the recent uptick in COVID-19 cases. New order growth accelerated from June's recent low, while employment rose slightly on the back of a renewed increase in backlogs of work. In the meantime, new export business was broadly stagnant as the pandemic continued to weigh on global demand. On the price front, the rate of input cost inflation quickened notably, while output charges posted the largest increase this year. Looking ahead, business sentiment picked up from June's nine-month low but remained softer than that seen on average over the series history.</preview>
        <date>2021-08-04</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Services Growth Slows to 14-Month Low: Caixin</title>
        <preview>The Caixin China General Services PMI fell to a 14-month low of 50.3 in June 2021 from 55.1 in the prior month, amid an outbreak of a more infectious Delta variant of COVID-19 in Guangdong and the subsequent imposition of anti-virus measures.. New orders grew the least since April 2020, while employment shrank for the first time in four months. Meantime, the gauge of new export business rose into positive territory, though the rate of expansion was marginal. Prices data showed inflationary pressure eased, with input cost inflation rising the least since September 2020 while output charges dropping for the first time in nearly a year. Looking ahead, sentiment remained strongly upbeat, though the degree of positive sentiment slipped to a nine-month low, amid concerns over the epidemic situation at home and abroad.</preview>
        <date>2021-07-05</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Services Growth Slows in May: Caixin</title>
        <preview>The Caixin China General Services PMI fell to 55.1 in May 2021 from a four-month high of 56.3 in the prior month, as COVID cases abroad hurt business activity. Still, the latest reading pointed to the 13th straight month of increase in the sector, with new order growth easing but remaining robust, while employment rising for the third month in a row. At the same time, export orders shrank for the third time in four months. Meanwhile, backlogs of work accumulated the most in over a year. Cost pressures continued to build, amid higher prices for raw materials, energy, staff, and transport. Notably, the rate of input cost inflation was the highest since November 2020. Prices charged, meantime increased again, with the rate of inflation the quickest so far this year. Finally, confidence was strongly positive, though the overall degree of optimism edged down to a four-month low.</preview>
        <date>2021-06-03</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Services Growth at 4-Month High: Caixin</title>
        <preview>The Caixin China General Services PMI increased to a four-month high of 56.3 in April 2021 from 54.3 in the prior month, amid the successful containment of COVID-19 and a further improvement in demand. New orders expanded at the fastest rate since last November on the back of a renewed upturn in export work; while employment rose further, with the rate of growth the fastest in five months. Prices gauges, meantime, remained at a high level and inflationary pressure heightened, as input cost rose faster due to increased staff and raw materials costs. Output charged also went up, though to a lesser extent than that seen for input costs. Looking ahead, confidence remained historically sharp, despite the level of positive sentiment slipped slightly from March's eight-year record.</preview>
        <date>2021-05-07</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Services PMI Rises to 3-Month High: Caixin</title>
        <preview>The Caixin China General Services PMI picked up to a three-month high of 54.3 in March 2021 from 51.5 in the previous month, amid a further recovery from the pandemic. The latest reading was also slightly higher than the series average, as domestic demand strengthened, with new orders expanding the most since December 2020. Also, employment returned to growth, while backlogs increased slightly following falls in the prior four months. Meantime, export orders fell for the second straight month, though the contraction was limited. On the cost front, inflationary pressure increased, with input rising for the ninth straight month while output prices expanding for the eight months in a row. Looking ahead, sentiment strengthened to its highest in over a decade amid hopes of post-pandemic recovery.</preview>
        <date>2021-04-06</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Services Activity Growth Slows to 10-Month Low</title>
        <preview>The Caixin China General Services PMI dropped to a ten-month low of 51.5 in February 2021 from 52.0 a month earlier, amid the COVID-19 crisis, and a recent rise in cases globally. New orders rose the least since May with export sales declining for the first time in four months, while employment fell again after a six-month period of growth. At the same time, there was another reduction in outstanding business, though the rate of depletion remained marginal. On the price front, input cost inflation was among the highest seen over the past decade, due to greater purchasing and staffing costs, while prices charged rose only modestly. Lastly, the degree of positive sentiment strengthened since January and was among the highest seen over the past eight years.</preview>
        <date>2021-03-03</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Services Sector Rises the Least in 9 Months: Caixin</title>
        <preview>The Caixin China General Services PMI dropped to a nine-month low of 52.0 in January 2021 from 56.3 a month earlier, due to a fresh wave of COVID-19 infections in some parts of the country. New orders rose the least since last August, export sales expanded at the softest rate in three months, and employment growth eased further from November's more than decade-high. On the price front, input costs rose the most since April 2012, while prices charged inflation eased to a three-month low. Finally, sentiment hit its lowest since September, due to uncertainty over the trajectory of the virus.</preview>
        <date>2021-02-03</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Services Growth Remains Solid: Caixin</title>
        <preview>The Caixin China General Services PMI fell to 56.3 in December 2020 from a more than a decade-high of 57.8 in November, amid ongoing recovery in consumer demand after the country curbed its COVID-19 outbreak. New order growth eased, while export sales rose modestly. At the same time, employment increased for the fifth straight month, which helped to reduce levels of backlogged work. Prices data revealed a further sharp rise in input costs, which led firms to increase their output charges at the steepest rate since January 2008. Looking ahead, business confidence improved to the highest since April 2011 due to hopes of a further rebound in global economic conditions.</preview>
        <date>2021-01-06</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Services Activity Soars in November: Caixin</title>
        <preview>The Caixin China General Services PMI rose to 57.8 in November 2020 from 56.8 in October, pointing to the second fastest growth in services activity in over a decade, amid a further recovery in consumer demand after the country curbed its COVID-19 outbreak. New orders expanded for the seventh month in a row, touching the highest level since April 2010. Also, new export orders advanced for the first time in five months and employment rose at the strongest rate since October 2010. On the cost front, inflation pressure became evident. The measures for input prices and prices that businesses charged both rose further into expansionary territory, hitting the highest readings since August 2010 and February 2010, respectively. Looking ahead, sentiment reached the highest point since April 2011.</preview>
        <date>2020-12-03</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Services Growth Accelerates in October</title>
        <preview>The Caixin China General Services PMI rose to 56.8 in October 2020, signaling a strong rate of growth in services output, and the second-fastest expansion since August 2010 as the economy continued to recovery from the COVID-19 pandemic. The pace of increase in new orders was the third-steepest since September 2010, despite a renewed fall in export sales, and employment rose the most in over a year. At the same time, outstanding workloads rose slightly, with the rate of accumulation having softened since September. On the price front, input cost inflation hit its highest in over two years, amid reports of higher staff and purchasing costs. Meantime, efforts to remain competitive led firms to raise their output prices slightly. Looking ahead, business sentiment strengthened to the highest level since April 2012.</preview>
        <date>2020-11-04</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Services Growth Accelerates: Caixin</title>
        <preview>The Caixin China General Services PMI rose to 54.8 in September 2020 from 54.0 a month earlier. This was the fifth straight month of growth in the sector and the steepest since June, amid a further recovery from the COVID-19 pandemic. New orders expanded faster, mainly led by domestic demand; and employment grew for the second month in a row. Meanwhile, new export orders remained in contractionary territory for seven of the last eight months. At the same time, backlogs of work have risen in three of the past four months. As for prices, input cost inflation dipped to a three-month low, while prices charged rose for the second straight month, but at a softer rate. Looking ahead, confidence remained strongly positive.</preview>
        <date>2020-10-09</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Services Growth Remains Solid: Caixin</title>
        <preview>The Caixin China General Services PMI stood at 54.0 in August 2020, little-changed from July's figure of 54.1, signaling a further solid increase in business activity amid ongoing resumption of work and normalization of market demand in the post-epidemic economic recovery. New orders rose markedly, despite easing further from June's recent record, while employment increased for the first time in seven months. Meantime, export orders fell for the second month in a row, while outstanding business dropped slightly following a mild rise in July. Prices data showed input costs rose the most since March, amid reports of higher staffing costs and raw material price. Output charges, meantime, rose after a slight reduction in July. Looking ahead, sentiment weakened to its lowest in three months.</preview>
        <date>2020-09-03</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Services Sector Expands at a Softer Pace</title>
        <preview>The Caixin China General Services PMI fell to 54.1 in July 2020 from an over 10-year high of 58.4 in June, pointing to the slowest expansion in the current three-month sequence of post-COVID recovery. New export business dropped sharply into contraction territory as the pandemic continued to hit other nations hard. Also, employment fell for the sixth consecutive month. Meantime, new orders rose for the third month in a row, maintaining its strong momentum; while outstanding business increased for the second straight month. On the price front, input costs rose while the prices that service providers charged customers declined slightly. Finally, sentiment strengthened to an over five-year high.</preview>
        <date>2020-08-05</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Services Growth Highest in Over A Decade</title>
        <preview>The Caixin China General Services PMI jumped to 58.4 in June 2020 from 55.0 in the previous month, pointing to the strongest growth in services activity since April 2010, widely attributed to the recent easing of virus-related restrictions and stronger demand conditions. New orders grew the most in nearly a decade as companies reported that greater customer numbers were resuming more normal business operations. In addition, export sales rose for the first time since January, amid improving global demand. Meantime, employment fell further generally linked to voluntary leaver and outstanding workloads went up for the first time in four months. On the price front, input cost dropped slightly, mainly due to lower staff-related costs while prices charged were broadly unchanged ending a six-month period of decline. According to respondents, competition for new work continued to limit overall pricing power. Looking ahead, business sentiment hit a three-year high.</preview>
        <date>2020-07-03</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Service Sector Rebounds Sharply</title>
        <preview>The Caixin China General Services PMI jumped to 55.0 in May 2020 from 44.4 in the previous month, pointing to the first month of growth in the service sector since January and the fastest since October 2010, as the economy recovers from strict coronavirus-led containment measures. New orders rose the most since September 2010, boosted by stronger domestic demand, while new export orders fell markedly as many key markets imposed public health measures to fight the pandemic. Meanwhile, employment declined again on signs of spare capacity and efforts to raise efficiency. On the price front, average input prices were broadly unchanged for the second month running, while output charges continued to fall as firms sought to stimulate sales. Looking ahead, sentiment remained strong, despite softening from the previous month.</preview>
        <date>2020-06-03</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Service Sector Contracts for 3rd Month</title>
        <preview>The Caixin China General Services PMI rose to 44.4 in April 2020 from 43.0 in the previous month, pointing to the third straight month of contraction in the sector due to weakening demand both at home and abroad amid the COVID-19 pandemic. New orders fell at a slower rate despite a near record fall in exports, and employment declined the most since data collection began in late-2005. On the price front, input costs were broadly stable in April, as firms discounted their selling prices again as part of attempts to boost new orders. Looking ahead, confidence picked up to a three-month high amid hopes of a recovery in conditions once the pandemic situation improves.</preview>
        <date>2020-05-07</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Service Contraction Eases in March: Caixin</title>
        <preview>The Caixin China General Services PMI rose to 43.0 in March 2020 from a record low of 26.5 in the previous month. This was the second-lowest reading since the survey began in 2005, amid concerns over the longevity and severity of the COVID-19 pandemic. New orders fell at a softer pace despite the substantial decline in export sales, while employment fell for the second straight month and at a steeper rate and the rate of backlog depletion was the quickest seen since September 2015. On the price front, average input costs rose after falling substantially, driven by increased overtime payments and investment into anti-virus equipment for staff. Meanwhile, selling prices dropped again and at the steepest rate since April 2009, as part of efforts to increase sales. Looking ahead, confidence picked up slightly from February's record low but remained historically weak.</preview>
        <date>2020-04-03</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Services Shrink at Record Pace: Caixin</title>
        <preview>The Caixin China General Services PMI plunged to a record low of 26.5 in February 2020 from 51.8 in the prior month, amid company closures and travel restrictions due to the damaging effect of the coronavirus on the economy. New orders, exports and employment all fell at the steepest rates on record. Consequently, backlogs of work rose substantially. On the price front, operating expenses declined at the fastest rate since the data collection started over 14 years ago, and selling prices were cut for the third in a row, and at a steeper rate. Looking ahead, business sentiment slipped to a survey low.</preview>
        <date>2020-03-04</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Services Growth Slows to 3-Month Low: Caixin</title>
        <preview>The Caixin China General Services PMI fell to 51.8 in January 2020 from 52.5 in the previous month, missing market consensus of 52.6. This was the weakest increase in the service sector output since October, as new orders grew the least in three months amid softening domestic demand, while employment broadly stagnated after expanding in each of the prior 15 months. Meantime, new export business accelerated on the back of improving Sino-US relations following a preliminary trade deal between the two countries. On the price front, input price inflation hit a 10-month low, while selling prices fell as some firms reduced their prices to help boost new order intakes. Lastly, sentiment strengthened to a 16-month high, boosted by planned company expansions, entry in to new markets, new product releases and signs of improving demand in the property sector.</preview>
        <date>2020-02-05</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Services Growth Slows in December: Caixin</title>
        <preview>The Caixin China General Services PMI fell to 52.5 in December 2019 from a seven-month high of 53.5 in the previous month. New business increased the most since September despite a slowdown in export order growth, while the rate of job creation was only marginal, with a number of companies adopting relatively cautious approaches to hiring amid efforts to contain costs and boost efficiency. Service providers recorded higher backlogs of work at the end of 2019, recovering from November's fall, as greater volumes of new work imparted pressure on capacities. On the price front, input cost inflation eased to a nine-month low, while output charges fell for the first time since September 2018. Finally, business sentiment edged down to the second-lowest on record, amid concerns over ongoing trade tensions, relatively subdued economic growth and staff shortages.</preview>
        <date>2020-01-06</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Services Activity Growth at 7-Month High</title>
        <preview>The Caixin China General Services PMI rose to a seven-month high of 53.5 in November 2019 from 51.1 in the previous month and beating market estimates of 52.7. New orders increased, as export orders accelerated to a four-month high. Meanwhile, the job creation rate dropped to a four-month low, with backlogs falling for the first time since August, albeit only slight. On the price front, input cost inflation slowed for the second consecutive month; and prices charged by service providers rose modestly, with the rate of increase little-changed from the prior three months. Looking ahead, sentiment improved, but was still notably weaker than the historical trend.</preview>
        <date>2019-12-04</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Services Growth Slows to 8-Month Low</title>
        <preview>The Caixin China General Services PMI unexpectedly fell to 51.1 in October 2019 from 51.3 in the previous month and missing market expectations of 52.8. This was the weakest pace of growth in the service sector since February, as new orders rose the least in eight months and employment growth was at three-month low, with overseas sales expanding modestly. Meantime, outstanding business went up at the fastest rate since February 2017, implying a mismatch between labor supply and demand. In terms of prices, input cost inflation slowed, while output charge increased marginally. Looking ahead, confidence softened to its lowest since July last year.</preview>
        <date>2019-11-05</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Services Grow The Least in 7 Months</title>
        <preview>The Caixin China General Services PMI fell to a seven-month low of 51.3 in September 2019 from 52.1 in the previous month and below market expectations of 52.9 as new orders and employment growth was offset by higher operating costs. New orders rose the most since January 2018, despite a softer increase in new export work, with a number of firms linking the upturn to new product releases and firmer client demand. In addition, employment growth was the quickest seen since January 2017 while backlogs of work were up for the first time since last December. On the price front, input cost inflation picked up to one-year high due to greater costs for labour, fuel and raw materials. Looking ahead, business optimism in the service sector slipped to its lowest since May.</preview>
        <date>2019-10-08</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Services Growth at 3-Month High</title>
        <preview>The Caixin China General Services PMI rose to a three-month high of 52.1 in August 2019 from 51.6 in the previous month. New orders rose the most in four months, with new export business increasing solidly, and the rate of job creation was the fastest since June 2018. Meantime, the amount of outstanding work declined slightly. On the price front, operating expenses rose at the strongest pace for three months amid reports of greater purchasing prices and labor costs, while output charges went up the most in 20 months. Looking ahead, business sentiment strengthened to a five-month high.</preview>
        <date>2019-09-04</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Services Growth Slows to 5-Month Low</title>
        <preview>The Caixin China General Services PMI fell unexpectedly to 51.6 in July 2019 from 52.0 in the previous month and missing market expectations of 52.0. The latest reading pointed to the weakest pace of expansion in the service sector since February, as new order growth slowed, despite a solid rebound in export sales at services companies, while employment rose marginally. On the price front, operating expenses rose further, with the rate of inflation strengthening slightly from the prior month, due to higher costs of materials, fuel and staff. Companies raised their charges slightly, with some indicating that competitive pressures had restricted pricing power. Finally, sentiment remained upbeat overall, with the degree of positive sentiment being unchanged from June.</preview>
        <date>2019-08-05</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Services Growth Slows to 4-Month Low: Caixin</title>
        <preview>The Caixin China General Services PMI dropped to a four-month low of 52.0 in June 2019 from 52.7 in the previous month and missing market expectations of 52.6. New work from abroad declined for the first time in nine months, with companies citing subdued global demand and tariffs. Still, overall new orders grew slightly faster, supported by fiscal policies that boosted client spending. Meanwhile, employment was broadly unchanged, as greater hiring to meet higher new business was weighed on by the non-replacement of voluntary leavers, while backlogs continued to fall. Price pressures remained historically subdued in June, as services firms saw a moderate increase in operating costs, reportedly linked to higher staff expenses and elevated purchasing activity. Looking ahead, service sector companies remained strongly optimistic.</preview>
        <date>2019-07-03</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Services Activity Slows More than Expected</title>
        <preview>The Caixin China General Services PMI dropped to 52.7 in May 2019 from 54.5 in the previous moth and missing market expectations of 54.3. The latest reading pointed to the weakest pace of expansion in the service sector since February, amid a slowdown in new orders mainly due to foreign demand and as the job creation rate eased. Additionally, backlogs of work fell further, though the rate of depletion remained marginal. On the price front, input cost inflation slowed and output prices advanced marginally. Looking ahead, sentiment weakened to its lowest since July last year amid subdued expectations linked to the ongoing trade dispute with the US and global demand conditions.</preview>
        <date>2019-06-05</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Services Growth Accelerates to 15-Month High: Markit</title>
        <preview>The Caixin China General Services PMI edged up unexpectedly to 54.5 in April 2019 from 54.4 in the previous month, easily beating market expectations of 52.8. The latest reading pointed to the strongest pace of expansion in the service sector since January 2018, as export sales grew the most since the survey began in September 2014 and employment rose at the fastest rate in ten months, amid improved marketing strategies, new product offerings and firmer underlying market demand. Meantime, outstanding workloads fell further, though the rate of backlog depletion was the slowest so far this year. On the price front, input price inflation hit its highest since September last year; while factory charges went up the most since June 2018, with some firms linking it to firmer demand conditions. Finally, sentiment reached its lowest in five months, due to concerns over the strength of the global economy.</preview>
        <date>2019-05-06</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Services Growth Accelerates to 14-Month High</title>
        <preview>The Caixin China General Services PMI jumped to 54.4 in March 2019 from 51.1 in the previous month, easily beating market consensus of 52.3. The latest reading pointed to the strongest pace of expansion in the service sector since January 2018, as new orders rose the most in 14 months, with new export sales advancing at the second-strongest rate since December 2017 amid reports of greater activity in international markets. In addition, employment growth was little-changed, while backlogs fell for the third straight month. On the price front, input cost inflation eased slightly and was moderate overall; while average selling prices rose marginally. Looking ahead, business sentiment strengthened to three-month high.</preview>
        <date>2019-04-03</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Services Growth Slows to 4-Month Low</title>
        <preview>The Caixin China General Services PMI fell to 51.1 in February 2019 from 53.6 in the previous month and missing market consensus of 53.5. The latest PMI reading pointed to the weakest growth in the service sector since October 2018, as new orders rose the least in four months, new export order growth slowed to a five month low and employment grew only marginally. At the same time, backlogs fell for the second straight month and hit its lowest figure since September 2015, reflecting downward pressure on overall orders. In terms of prices, both prices charged and input costs edged up. Looking ahead, sentiment continued to fall despite staying in positive territory.</preview>
        <date>2019-03-05</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Services Sector Growth Remains Solid</title>
        <preview>The Caixin China General Services PMI edged down to 53.6 in January 2019 from 53.9 in the previous month. The latest reading pointed to the weakest growth in the service sector since October 2018, mainly affected by weakening domestic demand and despite signs of progress in the Sino-US trade negotiations. New orders rose the most in seven months, new export orders expanded at the steepest pace in over a year, and employment growth accelerated to a 3-month high. Meanwhile, backlogs of work declined slightly. On the price front, input price inflation slowed to its lowest since May last year, while factory gate prices fell for the third month in a row and at a quicker rate. Finally, sentiment weakened. "The effects of China’s policies to support domestic demand and the development of the trade war between the country and the US will remain key to the prospects of the Chinese economy," said Zhengsheng Zhong, director of macroeconomic analysis at CEBM Group.</preview>
        <date>2019-02-03</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Services Growth Accelerates to 6-Month High</title>
        <preview>The Caixin China General Services PMI edged up unexpectedly to a 6-month high of 53.9 in December 2018 from 53.8 in the previous month, easily beating market expectations of 52.9. New orders increased modestly, the pace of job creation was only marginal, and new export business expanded at the fastest pace in six months as companies stepped up efforts to attract more orders from abroad. Meantime, unfinished business went up for the first time in four months, though only slightly. On the price front, operating expenses continued to increase solidly, with many firms linking the rise to higher raw material prices and salary costs; while selling prices went up a bit. Looking ahead, the level of positive sentiment towards the 12-month business outlook improved from November’s recent low.</preview>
        <date>2019-01-04</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Services Growth Accelerates to 5-Month High</title>
        <preview>The Caixin China General Services PMI jumped unexpectedly to a 5-month high of 53.8 in November 2018 from October’s 13-month low of 50.8 and well above market expectations of 50.7. New orders increased the most since June, despite a modest increase in new business from abroad, and employment grew for the second straight month. Meantime, outstanding business fell slightly for the third month in a row amid reports of greater efforts to clear backlogs. On the price front, input cost inflation was unchanged while selling prices went up a bit. At the same time, services companies expressed the weakest level of optimism since July, with a number of respondents citing concerns over the strength of future client demand and intense competition.</preview>
        <date>2018-12-05</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Service Sector Growth Slows to 13-Month Low</title>
        <preview>The Caixin China General Services PMI fell to 50.8 in October 2018 from 53.1 in the previous month and below market consensus of 52.9. The latest reading pointed to the weakest pace of expansion in the service sector since September 2017 due to the first stagnation of new business for nearly ten years amid the ongoing trade conflict with the US, while employment grew marginally on efforts to boost operational capacity after a slight reduction in September. Meantime, the amount of unfinished work fell for the second month running, with some companies reporting greater efforts to clear backlogs. That said, the rate of depletion remained marginal overall. On the price front, input prices continued to increase boosted by higher fuel and staff costs while prices charged rose slightly. Looking ahead, service providers signalled the weakest level of confidence since July.</preview>
        <date>2018-11-05</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Services Growth at 3-Month High in September</title>
        <preview>The Caixin China General Services PMI unexpectedly rose to a three-month high of 53.1 in September of 2018 from 51.5 in the previous month and beating market consensus of 51.4. New orders increased the most since June, pointing to some improvement in demand. Meantime, employment contracted for the first time in over two years, while outstanding workloads continued to fall. On the price front, input costs rose at the steepest rate since January, which could squeeze company profit margins. According to panelists, higher prices for fuel, raw materials and greater staffing costs all underpinned the latest increase in operating expenses. Meantime, firms signaled broadly no change to their output charges, with some mentioning greater efforts to remain competitive. Sentiment slipped amid concerns of ongoing global trade tensions and more restrictive environmental policies.</preview>
        <date>2018-10-08</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Services Growth Slows to 10-Month Low</title>
        <preview>The Caixin China General Services PMI fell to a 10-month low of 51.5 in August of 2018 from 52.8 in the previous month and missing market expectations of 52.7. Amid a steeper rise in input cost, employment rose moderately while new order growth picked up only slightly from July’s over two-year low. At the same time, sentiment improved a bit but remained below historical average. Meanwhile, backlogs of work were little-changed after a three-month sequence of reduction. The pace of charge inflation was marginal and similar to that seen in the previous month.</preview>
        <date>2018-09-05</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Services Growth Slows to 4-Month Low</title>
        <preview>The Caixin China General Services PMI fell to a four-month low of 52.8 in July of 2018 from 53.9 in the previous month and missing market expectations of 53.7. New orders expanded at weakest rate for over two-and-a-half years, employment growth eased and sentiment slumped to its lowest since October 2015. In addition, outstanding business declined further and the rate of backlog depletion was the quickest recorded since the start of 2016. On the price front, average input costs continued to rise due to higher fuel and raw material prices as well as greater salary costs; while services companies increased their charges at the joint-weakest rate since September 2017.</preview>
        <date>2018-08-03</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China June Services Growth at 4-Month High: Caixin</title>
        <preview>The Caixin China General Services PMI rose unexpectedly to 53.9 in June of 2018 from 52.9 in the previous month, easily beating market consensus of 52.7. It was the highest reading in four months, as both new orders and employment increased slightly faster. Meanwhile, outstanding workloads fell marginally for the second month in a row. On the price front, input costs rose the most since February, and average charged inflation hit a three-month high. The index of business expectations, a gauge of companies’ confidence towards the 12-month outlook, dipped from a recent high seen in May.</preview>
        <date>2018-07-04</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Services Growth Steady in May</title>
        <preview>The Caixin China General Services PMI stood at 52.9 in May of 2018, the same as in the previous month and matching market consensus. New order growth eased while employment grew the most in four months and sentiment remained optimistic. At the same time, backlogs of work declined after rising in the prior two months. On the prices front, input price inflation picked up. Meanwhile, competitive pressures reportedly restricted the overall pricing power of service providers, with their charges increasing at the slowest rate for eight months.</preview>
        <date>2018-06-05</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Services Growth Beats Estimates</title>
        <preview>The Caixin China General Services PMI rose to 52.9 in April of 2018 from a four-month low of 52.3 in March and above market consensus of 52.2. New orders went up at a faster pace, employment continued to grow and sentiment improved slightly. Meantime, input prices increased the least in six months, leading to a softer rise in prices charged. "The operating conditions of the service sector improved more significantly than the manufacturing sector," said Zhengsheng Zhong, director of macroeconomic analysis at CEBM Group.</preview>
        <date>2018-05-04</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Services Growth Slows to 4-Month Low: Caixin</title>
        <preview>The Caixin China General Services PMI fell unexpectedly to a four-month low of 52.3 in March of 2018 from 54.2 in February and missing market expectations of 54.5. The latest reading pointed to a modest increase in services activity, as new order growth softened and employment rose the least in 19 months. In addition, optimism fell to a six-month low, while outstanding business went up slightly following broadly stagnant backlogs over the opening two months of the year. On the price front, input cost inflation eased to a four-month low and charge inflation picked up from February.</preview>
        <date>2018-04-04</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Services Sector Growth Slows in February</title>
        <preview>The Caixin China Services PMI fell to 54.2 in February of 2018 from a 68-month high of 54.7 in the prior month and slightly below market consensus of 54.3. New order growth softened slightly while employment continued to rise. At the same time, sentiment strengthened from January's four-month low, supported by new marketing strategies, upcoming projects and expectations that market conditions will continue to improve. Elsewhere, providers saw a solid rise in cost burdens despite the pace of inflation easing from January’s 69-month record. However, firms were still able to raise modestly their charges. The services sector accounts for over half of China’s economy, with rising wages providing its consumers more spending power.</preview>
        <date>2018-03-05</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Services Sector Growth at Near 6 Year-High: Caixin</title>
        <preview>The Caixin China Services PMI unexpectedly rose to 54.7 in January of 2018 from 53.9 in the prior month and beating market consensus of 53.6. The reading pointed to the strongest pace of expansion in the services sector since May 2012, as new order increased the most in 32 months and employment went up at the fastest rate in five months. Meantime, sentiment reached its lowest in four months, driven by concerns that economic conditions may soften. Elsewhere, backlogs of work were unchanged. Input cost hit the highest since April 2012, due to the impact of rising labor costs and increasing crude oil prices. However, prices charged fell again, suggesting that firms have failed to fully pass higher costs on to consumers.</preview>
        <date>2018-02-05</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Services Sector Growth at Over 3-Year High</title>
        <preview>The Caixin China Services PMI unexpectedly jumped to 53.9 in December of 2017 from 51.9 in November and beating market consensus of 51.8. The figure pointed to the the strongest pace of expansion in the service sector since August 2014, as new business increased the most since May 2015 and business optimism improved to a six-month high. Input price inflation matched March's four-year high, on raw materials, transportation and salaries, while output charge inflation was little-changed from the previous month. The PMI averaged 52.1 in 2017, almost unchanged from an annual average of 52.2 in 2016.</preview>
        <date>2018-01-04</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Services Sector Growth at 3-Month High</title>
        <preview>The Caixin China Services PMI rose to 51.9 in November of 2017 from 51.2 in October and above market consensus of 51.5. It was the strongest growth in services activity since August, as new orders increased the most in three months, employment grew further and confidence strengthened. At the same time, input costs and prices charged continued to rise while the level of work-in-hand dropped for the third straight month. Meantime, services providers raised their prices charged at a modest pace, which was the quickest since July 2015.</preview>
        <date>2017-12-05</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Services Sector Growth Beats Estimates</title>
        <preview>The Caixin China Services PMI rose to 51.2 in October of 2017 from a 21 month-low of 50.6 in September and above market consensus of 50.8. Business confidence improved slightly while new orders growth was modest and job creation remained marginal. At the same time, services providers were able to raise their prices at the fastest pace in over two years. Meanwhile, the sub-indices of input prices and prices charged continued to go up. The level of work-in-hand dropped for the second straight month. The latest reading was much weaker than the historical average.</preview>
        <date>2017-11-03</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Services Sector Growth at 21-Month Low</title>
        <preview>The Caixin China Services PMI unexpectedly declined to 50.6 in September of 2017 from 52.7 in August, way below market consensus of 53.1. The reading pointed to the weakest pace of expansion in the service sector since December 2015, as both new orders and employment rose at a slower pace and confidence softened. Also, the level of outstanding work at Chinese services companies declined during September, after a four-month sequence of accumulation. On the price front, input cost inflation picked up for the second month in a row while output charges set by services companies rose only slightly during September.</preview>
        <date>2017-10-09</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Services Sector Growth at 3-Month High in August</title>
        <preview>The Caixin China Services PMI rose to 52.7 in August of 2017 from 51.5 in July and beating market consensus of 51.8. It was the fastest expansion in services activity since May, as new orders increased solidly, employment went up the most in four months and business confidence strengthened. At the same time, backlog accumulation rose the least in four months. Average input prices increased at the slowest rate in more than eight years while prices charged declined for the first time in nearly 1-1/2 years amid reports of greater market competition.</preview>
        <date>2017-09-05</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Services Sector Growth Slows In July</title>
        <preview>The Caixin China Services PMI edged down to 51.5 in July of 2017 from 51.6 in June while markets expected 51.9. The print matched the level in April, which was the lowest since May 2016. New orders rose the least in 16 months and business sentiment hit its lowest since November 2016. At the same time, job creation held close to June's 10-month low and outstanding business accumulated at the rate similar to those seen in the prior two months. Input cost inflation came in at its lowest level in nearly a year while prices charged rose marginally.</preview>
        <date>2017-08-03</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Services Sector Growth Eases In June</title>
        <preview>The Caixin China Services PMI unexpectedly fell to 51.6 in June of 2017 from a four-month high of 52.8 in May while markets expected 52.9. New orders rose the least in over a year, employment grew at the slowest pace in 10 months although companies remained optimistic. At the same time, outstanding business was little-changed from the prior month and average input prices increased the least since October 2016. Meantime, output charges went up marginally, with some firms mentioning greater market competition had weighed on their ability to raise prices.</preview>
        <date>2017-07-05</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Services Sector Growth At 4-Month High</title>
        <preview>The Caixin China Services PMI rose to 52.8 in May of 2017 from 51.5 in April and marking the highest reading since January. New business increased the most in five months and employment went up further while business confidence improved slightly. In addition, cost pressures intensified, due to greater prices for raw materials and higher staff costs, whereas prices charged fell for the second straight month.</preview>
        <date>2017-06-05</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Services Sector Growth At 11-Month Low In April</title>
        <preview>The Caixin China Services PMI fell to 51.5 in April of 2017 from 52.2 in March and missing market consensus of 52.6. It was the lowest reading since May 2016, as employment rose the least so far this year and business confidence softened to its five-month low while new business expanded marginally. At the same time, cost pressures eased as input prices rose the least in six months and output prices went up slightly from their March levels.</preview>
        <date>2017-05-04</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Services Sector Growth At 6-Month Low In March</title>
        <preview>The Caixin China Services PMI fell to 52.2 in March of 2017 from 52.6 in February and missing market consensus of 53.2. It was the lowest reading since September 2016, due to a slowdown in new business and employment while cost pressures intensified. In March, new business rose the least in six months and employment went up at the slowest pace so far this year. Meantime, input prices soared to their highest in more than four years, although companies were able to pass on part of the costs to customers. "Weaker increases in new business have clouded the economic outlook, and investors should watch closely for signs of a turning point in the second quarter,” said Dr. Zhengsheng Zhong, Director of Macroeconomic Analysis at CEBM Group.</preview>
        <date>2017-04-06</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Services Sector Growth At 4-Month Low</title>
        <preview>The Caixin China Services PMI fell to 52.6 in February of 2017 from 53.1 in January and missing market consensus of 53.3. It was the lowest reading since October 2016, as growth in new business was unchanged from the prior month while the rate of payroll expansion weakened slightly from the 20-month record seen in January. Meanwhile, backlogs of work increased the most since the start of 2010 and the rise in cost burdens was the lowest since last November last year. Optimism towards future activity growth fell slightly from January's 11-month high.</preview>
        <date>2017-03-03</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Services Sector Growth Slows In January</title>
        <preview>The Caixin China Services PMI fell to 53.1 in January of 2017 from 17-month high of 53.4 in December and below market consensus of 53.6. Output and new orders rose at slower paces while employment increased the most since May 2015 and business sentiment hit 18-month high. At the same time, the amount of unfinished work increased while the backlog accumulated marginally. Companies reported higher cost burdens, with the rate of inflation edging up to the fastest in 47 months. Also, producers went up their prices at a faster pace but remained marginal overall.</preview>
        <date>2017-02-06</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Services Sector Growth at 17-Month High</title>
        <preview>The Caixin China Services PMI rose to 53.4 in December of 2016 from 53.1 in November while market expected 53.3. It was the fastest growth since July 2015, as new orders rose the most in 17 months and business expectations went up to a four-month high while employment growth eased modestly. At the same time, backlogged work was broadly unchanged while input costs rose at the fastest rate in nearly two years. Services companies raised slightly their prices charged amid reports that competitive market pressures had restricted their ability to fully pass on higher input costs.</preview>
        <date>2017-01-05</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Services Sector Grows the Most in 16 Months</title>
        <preview>The Caixin China Services PMI rose to 53.1 in November of 2016 from 52.4 in October and beating market consensus of 52.7. It was the fastest growth since July 2015, as new orders rose modestly and employment went up at the fastest pace in 1-1/2-years while business expectations eased to a 13-month low. Meantime, unfinished workloads rose for the second month running while price pressures were relatively muted. "Price inflation, rather than a structural improvement, seems to be the main reason behind the recent recovery of the economy in general. The economy may remain stable in the fourth quarter, but it will still face significant downward pressure next year," said Dr. Zhengsheng Zhong, director of Macroeconomic Analysis at CEBM Group.</preview>
        <date>2016-12-05</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Services Sector Grows the Most in 4 Months</title>
        <preview>The Caixin China Services PMI rose to 52.4 in October of 2016 from 52.0 in September. It was the fastest growth since June but slightly below market consensus of 52.5. While business expectations were more positive than a month earlier, new orders increased the most since June. Employment also went up for the second straight month and the fastest pace since January. Meanwhile, backlogs of work increased slightly, ending a four-month sequence of marginal contraction. Input prices rose at a moderate pace across services companies. Prices charged were little-changed from the previous month, with some companies mentioning that increased competitive pressures had limited their pricing power. "It may be possible to sustain this stable condition throughout the fourth quarter, but it’s important that supportive policies are not relaxed because the economy still lacks sufficient growth momentum, " said Dr. Zhengsheng Zhong, director of Macroeconomic Analysis at CEBM Group.</preview>
        <date>2016-11-03</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Services Sector Growth Remains Solid in September</title>
        <preview>The Caixin China Services PMI stood at 52.0 in September of 2016 from 52.1 in August. While business expectations were much lower than in a month earlier, new orders rose modestly and employment grew for the first time since June. In the meantime, the average input cost increased the most in three months. Services companies noted a marginal drop in outstanding business for the fourth month in a row. "Overall, the economy continued to grow in September, but the rate of expansion fell two months in a row. Fiscal policy needs to continue to support the economy, because there is insufficient growth momentum on its own," said Dr. Zhengsheng Zhong, director of Macroeconomic Analysis at CEBM Group.</preview>
        <date>2016-10-08</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Services Sector Growth Accelerates in August</title>
        <preview>The Caixin China Services PMI rose to 52.1 in August of 2016 from 51.7 in July as business expectations rose the most in six months, employment stabilised and new orders grew at a slower pace. At the same time, firms saw a marginal rate of cost inflation that was the slowest since January 2015.</preview>
        <date>2016-09-05</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Services Sector Growth Eases in July</title>
        <preview>The Caixin China Services PMI unexpectedly fell to 51.7 in July of 2016 from an 11-month high of 52.7 in June and market consensus of 52.9. Activity and new order slowed while employment fell for first time in 4 months. The amount of unfinished work declined for the 2nd straight month while efforts to clear backlogs increased. Services companies maintained a positive stance towards future business activity in July, with the degree of optimism edging up to a 3-month high.</preview>
        <date>2016-08-03</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Services PMI Rebounds to 11-Month High</title>
        <preview>The Caixin China Services PMI rose to 52.7 in June of 2016 from 51.2 in May and market consensus of 52.3. It was the highest reading since July 2015, driven by a further rise in total new business while payrolls expanded slightly. At the same time, unfinished work declined for the first time in three months. Some companies reported increased efforts to clear backlogs due to greater amounts of incoming new work. Sustained cost inflation was seen across China’s service sector, with the rate of input price inflation picking up to a four-month high.</preview>
        <date>2016-07-05</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Services PMI at 3-Month Low</title>
        <preview>The Caixin China Services PMI stood at 51.2 in May of 2016, down from 51.8 in April and missing market consensus. It was the weakest reading since March as new orders rose at a slower pace and less than the historical average while job creation eased to marginal rate. Meanwhile, business expectations dropped to the lowest in five months but most respondents remained optimistic. "The government needs to continue to push forward stabilising measures to help the economy recover. It should also relax the control and regulation of the services sector to enable it to realize its growth potential and to facilitate the transformation and healthy development of the economy, " Director of Macroeconomic Analyst at CEBM Group, Zhengseng Zhong, said.</preview>
        <date>2016-06-03</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Services Sector Growth Less Than Expected</title>
        <preview>The Caixin China Services PMI came in at 51.8 in April of 2016, down from 52.2 in March and missing market consensus of 52.6. Despite softer growth in activity, new orders rose the most in three months and companies raised their staff numbers. Average input costs continued their upward trend, with the rate of inflation picking up slightly. Sustained cost inflation contributed to a renewed rise in prices charged by service providers.</preview>
        <date>2016-05-05</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Services PMI Rises in March</title>
        <preview>The Caixin General Services PMI in China came in at 52.2 in March of 2016, up from 51.2 in February and beating expectations of 51.4. While new orders rose modestly, employment fell for the first time since August 2013. Service providers reported lower selling price, citing greater competition. "Overall, the services sector developed well, but the economy is riding choppy waves, indicating the lack of a solid foundation for a recovery," He Fan, chief economist at Caixin Insight Group said.</preview>
        <date>2016-04-06</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Services Activity Falls in February</title>
        <preview>The Caixin General Services PMI in China unexpectedly dropped to 51.2 in February of 2016 from 52.4 in January and below market consensus of 52.6. Slower increases in both activity and new orders contributed to a weaker expansion of staff numbers in the service sector. Meanwhile, input costs rose slightly for the first time in a year-and-a-half.</preview>
        <date>2016-03-03</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Services Activity at 6-Month High</title>
        <preview>The Caixin General Services PMI in China rose to 52.4 in January of 2016 from to 50.2 in December 2015 from 51.2 in November and well above market consensus of 50.5. It is the highest reading since July 2015, as new business edged up while employment rose to the fastest in six months. Meanwhile, prices charged continued to be in a deflationary territory for a fifth straight month. Although the overall degree of positive sentiment improved, it remained much weaker than the series long-run average.</preview>
        <date>2016-02-03</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Caixin Services PMI at 17-Month Low</title>
        <preview>Services PMI in China fell to 50.2 in December of 2015 from 51.2 in November and below market consensus. It is the lowest reading since July 2014 and also the second lowest in survey history, largely due to softer client demand and greater competition.</preview>
        <date>2016-01-06</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Services PMI Below Forecasts</title>
        <preview>The Caixin General Services PMI in China dropped to 51.2 in November of 2015 from a three-month high in October of 52.0 and below market expectations. Growth in new business was the slowest in 16 months. Employment also increased with the rate of job creation easing to a marginal pace that was the second weakest for a year-and-a half. While outstanding business continued to fall across the services sector, business confidence were slightly up from October's record low, as a number of companies expressed concerns over a challenging economic outlook.</preview>
        <date>2015-12-03</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Services Activity at 3-Month High</title>
        <preview>The Caixin General Services PMI in China was at 52.0 in October of 2015, up from 50.5 in September and above market consensus. The reading was the highest since July, as service sector companies saw a further rise in total new business while employment also increased. Still, business sentiment at services companies eased to the lowest in survey history.</preview>
        <date>2015-11-04</date>
    </news>
    <news>
        <title>China Caixin Services PMI Lowest Since July 2014</title>
        <preview>The Caixin General Services PMI in China decreased to 50.50 in September of 2015, from 51.50 in August and missing market expectations. It is the lowest level since July 2014. New business expanded at the slowest pace in a year and companies had to cut prices for the first time in three months. However, more jobs were created than in a previous month and business expectations remained high. For the last two years, services have contributed the most to China's economic expansion.</preview>
        <date>2015-10-01</date>
    </news>
</root>
